[SPEAKER_04]: You were born here in, is it Napa or Napa?
[SPEAKER_04]: Napa.
[SPEAKER_04]: Napa?
[SPEAKER_04]: In January 16th, 1894?
[SPEAKER_04]: Ninety-five.
[SPEAKER_03]: Ninety-five.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: The record book says ninety-four, huh?
[SPEAKER_03]: How old are you?
[SPEAKER_04]: Eighty-three, right?
[SPEAKER_04]: Eighty-three, yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: Eighty-three last January.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did your family always live here?
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh, yes.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yes, they always lived here.
[SPEAKER_04]: And did your father play ball?
[SPEAKER_04]: No.
[SPEAKER_04]: He was a farmer.
[SPEAKER_04]: I see.
[SPEAKER_04]: Where did his father come from?
[SPEAKER_04]: Someplace else?
[SPEAKER_04]: Italy.
[SPEAKER_04]: He came from Italy.
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh, he was?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_04]: How'd he happen to settle out here, I wonder?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, this is a wine country, you know, and there's a lot of Italians settled here from Italy.
[SPEAKER_03]: Lots of them.
[SPEAKER_03]: And you find, if you look through the phone book, you see a lot of Italian names, fourth and fifth generation, now.
[SPEAKER_03]: I see.
[SPEAKER_03]: And that's the kind we used to have at home.
[SPEAKER_03]: At least I can think of five hotels that were run by Italians, four Italian people.
[SPEAKER_03]: They worked on the vineyards and the fruits and the tanneries.
[SPEAKER_03]: Where'd you first play ball?
[SPEAKER_03]: You had a sandlot ball around here?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh yeah, right here.
[SPEAKER_03]: We had a little team called the Alta Heights.
[SPEAKER_03]: We used to play with St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_03]: Our main opponent was St. Helena.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Dutch Juni was one of the St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was also a ballplayer professional afterwards.
[SPEAKER_03]: Juni.
[SPEAKER_03]: J-U-N-I-Y.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's dead now.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's been gone quite a little while.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, this was around 1906 and 7 and 8.
[SPEAKER_03]: We were kids.
[SPEAKER_04]: What position did you play in those days?
[SPEAKER_03]: First base.
[SPEAKER_03]: Always first base.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you have a high school here in Napa you went to?
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you play on the team there?
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you have a team?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Caught without a mask one day.
[SPEAKER_03]: That finished me in for catching.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh?
[SPEAKER_03]: What happened?
[SPEAKER_03]: It hit me in the eye.
[SPEAKER_03]: Why didn't you have a mask on?
[SPEAKER_03]: We didn't have any masks.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_03]: We didn't have any.
[SPEAKER_03]: Or at least they forgot it.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_04]: And you went out of St. Mary's, right?
[SPEAKER_03]: St. Mary's, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: What did you plan to do at St. Mary's?
[SPEAKER_03]: What was your major field?
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you have anything in particular?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I was in the banking at St. Mary's.
[SPEAKER_03]: I had a course there, a banking course.
[SPEAKER_03]: I took that and then I went into baseball.
[SPEAKER_04]: You had a pretty good team there, didn't you?
[SPEAKER_03]: Same night?
[SPEAKER_03]: Same night, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, we had a pretty good team.
[SPEAKER_03]: We used to play the Coastal Leagues during spring training.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you ever beat them?
[SPEAKER_03]: Once in a while.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't think we ever did while I was playing, but the team before me did.
[SPEAKER_03]: We had some pretty good players, like Tiny Leonard and Dutch Leonard.
[SPEAKER_03]: Dutch Leonard, huh?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: In fact, they beat the Red Sox at 2-1.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think he beat them 2-1.
[SPEAKER_03]: They were training out here.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you play ball all year round out here in the good weather, or most of the year?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, most of the year we played.
[SPEAKER_04]: I noticed in the recent draft choices, so many of them come from the West Coast.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, sure.
[SPEAKER_03]: The weather is so, you know, you can play most any day.
[SPEAKER_04]: What year did you finish up at St. Mary's?
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh, that was... Fifteen or so?
[SPEAKER_03]: What do you mean?
[SPEAKER_03]: Sixteen.
[SPEAKER_03]: Sixteen, right.
[SPEAKER_03]: And who signed you for Cleveland?
[SPEAKER_03]: Two of the students at St. Mary's.
[SPEAKER_03]: Not for Cleveland, but for Portland.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's why I started with Portland.
[SPEAKER_03]: Cleveland, Mr. Bernard, he was the vice president of Cleveland when I met him.
[SPEAKER_04]: I see.
[SPEAKER_03]: You mean to see you?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, to see the manager of the Portland Club.
[SPEAKER_03]: I didn't know anything about it, you know.
[SPEAKER_04]: Was this McCready running Portland then?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, Walter McCready.
[SPEAKER_03]: His uncle, I think, was the president.
[SPEAKER_03]: So the St. Mary's students recommended you?
[SPEAKER_03]: Two of them.
[SPEAKER_03]: Both of them.
[SPEAKER_03]: They're both alive, two of them.
[SPEAKER_04]: Portland signed you then?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: And that was your first year in Melbourne?
[SPEAKER_04]: That's my first year.
[SPEAKER_04]: 1916?
[SPEAKER_04]: 1916, yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: How'd you... was it a pretty big thrill going up there to the Coast League?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: Didn't think too much about it?
[SPEAKER_03]: Never very much of it now.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, of course it was fun.
[SPEAKER_03]: We were at the spring training, Sacramento, the three of us, Charlie Holliker, Carson Bigby, and myself, the three of us.
[SPEAKER_03]: They didn't have very many, what they called, butchers in those days, you know.
[SPEAKER_03]: Just a few of us.
[SPEAKER_03]: And it was funny, one of the three of us went up in the big league.
[SPEAKER_03]: Holliker was with the... Yeah, he was a good one, too.
[SPEAKER_04]: What happened?
[SPEAKER_04]: He sucked in your gum with him.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, he just thought he was sick.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, he was a beautiful player.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, there used to be pictures of him in the Sporting News, I guess, when he was just coming up with a great future, you know, for Big VX.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, yeah, that's right, yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: So Bernard signed you then, is that right?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: And did you get much money from Cleveland?
[SPEAKER_04]: Not very much.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you join the team then, the end of the season?
[SPEAKER_03]: Not the end of the season.
[SPEAKER_03]: During the season, in August, I think it was.
[SPEAKER_03]: I met him in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_03]: Who was their first baseman?
[SPEAKER_03]: Gando.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, Chick Gando.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: He was from around here, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, he just died recently.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was in Calisoga.
[SPEAKER_03]: His home was Berkeley, I think, originally from Berkeley.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was involved there.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: And so you got a few games?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, a few.
[SPEAKER_03]: Not very many.
[SPEAKER_03]: And the war came on and that finished it.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, did you go to training in 17th?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, down in New Orleans.
[SPEAKER_04]: You got in, it says here, about 73 games that year.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, something like that.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, but you got to be playing every day.
[SPEAKER_03]: You got to be playing every day.
[SPEAKER_03]: from one day to the other, you know.
[SPEAKER_04]: Lee Fole, managing the team?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, Lee Fole.
[SPEAKER_03]: How'd you like him?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I liked him very much.
[SPEAKER_03]: And after that, Speaker was kind of it.
[SPEAKER_04]: I guess I heard, who was it, George Uley or somebody told me that Speaker used to really call the shots almost from center field occasionally for a fall on the bench.
[SPEAKER_04]: Like pitcher changes.
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: What he had was Jack Rainey with him then?
[SPEAKER_03]: Jack Rainey was there, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Steve O'Neill?
[SPEAKER_03]: Warmbier was there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Warmbier, Joe Warmbier.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a dear, friendly neighbor of ours.
[SPEAKER_03]: Joe Sewell.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, Chapman was there first.
[SPEAKER_03]: Barry Gardner.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was thinking about it last night.
[SPEAKER_03]: I saw a little of the page from the television.
[SPEAKER_03]: When he'd catch the ball, he'd look at it before he threw it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: I don't know what he was doing, but you'd always get it there at Edelman.
[SPEAKER_04]: How about Kowalewski?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, Sammy.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, we interviewed him out in South Bend.
[SPEAKER_04]: Where did you live in Manuka?
[SPEAKER_03]: South Bend.
[SPEAKER_03]: South Bend, wow.
[SPEAKER_03]: Used to live in Pennsylvania.
[SPEAKER_03]: Shemokin.
[SPEAKER_03]: Shemokin, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: O'Neal's from Manuka.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, that's right.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, Kowalewski goes fishing every day.
[SPEAKER_04]: We saw Joey Sewell last year down in Tuscaloosa.
[SPEAKER_04]: It was the week before he went up to the Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_04]: What happened to Luke?
[SPEAKER_04]: He's in good shape.
[SPEAKER_04]: He's in Akron, Ohio.
[SPEAKER_04]: I spent a morning with him a few years ago.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, he's a very nice photographer.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, they're nice boys.
[SPEAKER_03]: You know, Horst Stevenson.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, we talked him in Tuscaloosa.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is he in Tuscaloosa?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, the neighbor, Joey Sewell.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I heard about him before he was...
[SPEAKER_03]: He played football.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you play football at St. Lawrence?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, I used to.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, we had Riggins and Stevenson and Joey Sewell.
[SPEAKER_04]: That was convenient there, right?
[SPEAKER_04]: At the same time.
[SPEAKER_04]: Alabama had some great ball teams there.
[SPEAKER_03]: They had the Sewells and Stevenson.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you get Joe Evans?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's a doctor in Meridian, I think, Mississippi.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was an infielder, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_03]: Outfielder.
[SPEAKER_04]: Elmer Smith.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, Elmer Smith.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was pretty close to Joe Evans, was that it?
[SPEAKER_04]: I don't think they mentioned him.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, no, I don't think so.
[SPEAKER_03]: I met Elmer back in France during the war.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was with the mortuary outfit.
[SPEAKER_03]: I had to get a picture of the two talking.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's true.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did that affect your career?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, yes, sure.
[SPEAKER_03]: It slowed me up
[SPEAKER_03]: I was gassed and gassed and gouging.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, well, yes, it slowed me up quite a bit.
[SPEAKER_03]: In fact, nearly all the ballplayers were in active action, you know, sort of, but I found to carry that rifle along, I weighed about nine pounds, you know, and all the stuff that you go through,
[SPEAKER_03]: You don't play ball during that time either, you know.
[SPEAKER_04]: When did you come back, in 19?
[SPEAKER_03]: 19, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you play ball at all for a while there?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I went back to, the next year I went back to Cleveland, but, let's just say it was, I still belonged, that's the year they won the pennants, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: 1920.
[SPEAKER_04]: You still have property there?
[SPEAKER_03]: I still have property, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you play with some minor team?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, Oakland.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oakland.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, they loaned me to Oakland.
[SPEAKER_03]: Then I went back up there.
[SPEAKER_03]: In 1923, I came back.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, you had parts of 1922 and 1923 you were up there.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you play much ball after that on the coast again?
[SPEAKER_03]: Not very much.
[SPEAKER_03]: I played with Oakland, finished with Oakland, up until 1927.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, you played then on April and those guys with the Seals?
[SPEAKER_03]: The Seals, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I tell you, they had a good ball club.
[SPEAKER_04]: Gilbert and... Roy Johnson.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: They had a good ball club.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was a good league.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Those things was a good league.
[SPEAKER_03]: Who was your manager at Oakland?
[SPEAKER_03]: Ivan Howard.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, he was at the St. Louis Browns in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_03]: Where was he playing?
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a infielder, second baseman.
[SPEAKER_03]: His brother Dale was with the Cubs for years.
[SPEAKER_03]: He didn't know that he was in Iowa.
[SPEAKER_03]: I didn't know that, no.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, yeah, he was with the Browns for quite a while.
[SPEAKER_04]: How would you play out here, Coach, when you were saved with playing the Seals?
[SPEAKER_04]: You didn't have the same ballpark that Oakland had their own.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, Oakland had their own ballpark.
[SPEAKER_03]: But they used to do it.
[SPEAKER_03]: On Thursdays, when one of them was visiting,
[SPEAKER_03]: We'd play in Oakland Thursday afternoon and Sunday morning in San Francisco, too.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, Sunday morning in Oakland.
[SPEAKER_03]: Thursday and Sunday morning we played in Oakland and we'd go to San Francisco.
[SPEAKER_04]: Sunday morning?
[SPEAKER_03]: Sunday morning, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was a big deal.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, it was very good.
[SPEAKER_03]: About to see it on Sunday morning.
[SPEAKER_03]: You'd have a long series, though, wouldn't you?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: Over 200 games.
[SPEAKER_03]: We played way over 200 games, yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did Tony Lozera have his big year out?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, with Salt Lake.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: And how about Paul Strand?
[SPEAKER_03]: Paul Strand.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was breaking my hand.
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh, what happened there?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, the ball was thrown up the line, see?
[SPEAKER_03]: And Paul was coming down, and I reached in to get the ball and hit him.
[SPEAKER_03]: Broke my wrist in three or four places.
[SPEAKER_03]: a long time I couldn't use that hand.
[SPEAKER_03]: He had a good year, I guess.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh yeah, he sure did.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, he couldn't do a thing in it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, it's funny, isn't it?
[SPEAKER_04]: The number of players that fit that category, you know.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I think a lot of it is mental, you know.
[SPEAKER_03]: They get up there with the biggies and they start thinking about it, instead of going right along like they used to.
[SPEAKER_03]: Of course, he had everything for them,
[SPEAKER_03]: Was he with Salt Lake, too?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Was there something about the atmosphere up there with the shell coast hitters?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, it was light.
[SPEAKER_03]: You had to get over the fence with your fists.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was gorgeous.
[SPEAKER_03]: I liked the playing.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, it was high.
[SPEAKER_04]: Hazel was there.
[SPEAKER_04]: He had 60 home runs in, I guess.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Earl Shaley and Bunny Brief.
[SPEAKER_03]: Bunny Brief.
[SPEAKER_03]: Remember him?
[SPEAKER_04]: Tony.
[SPEAKER_03]: Glenn Wright had some stories about Bunny Brief.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Look at him.
[SPEAKER_03]: In Traverse City, Michigan?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, he's named Grifolowski.
[SPEAKER_03]: Was that right?
[SPEAKER_03]: Grifolowski.
[SPEAKER_03]: A lot of those Polish fellas cut their names down, you know.
[SPEAKER_03]: I wonder where he got the bunny from.
[SPEAKER_04]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_04]: Very masculine.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, he's a good-looking guy.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, who are some of the stars that coached the others?
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, let's see.
[SPEAKER_04]: Mayo's?
[SPEAKER_04]: Augusta Mayo's.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: It was all clear in 1920, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, it was.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_03]: He owned the Panetone.
[SPEAKER_03]: He just passed away a year or two ago, a couple years ago.
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you know Jimmy O'Donnell?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: O'Connell.
[SPEAKER_03]: O'Connell, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's a tragic thing.
[SPEAKER_04]: Has he ever talked much about that?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: We passed through Bakersfield, and I was thinking I'd stop and talk to him, but if he'd met me, he wouldn't want to talk to me.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, it's a terrible thing.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, boy.
[SPEAKER_04]: He was just there.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yes, he did.
[SPEAKER_04]: He shouldn't have done it, but he didn't really know what he was doing.
[SPEAKER_04]: No, of course not.
[SPEAKER_04]: And Landis was kind of... Landis was a rough one.
[SPEAKER_04]: I suppose that kind of thing happening so soon after the Black Sox made Landis... Sure did.
[SPEAKER_04]: ...probably overreact, I suppose.
[SPEAKER_03]: Talk about czar.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was one, believe me.
[SPEAKER_03]: You'll never have another one.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, not like him.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you bat against Walter Jensen?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: Was that an experience?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, it was.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'm not mistaken.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think I did pretty well against him.
[SPEAKER_03]: In fact, Rick Owens is an umpire, and I was hitting him pretty good.
[SPEAKER_03]: Line drive, but at somebody.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, what's the matter with Rick?
[SPEAKER_03]: I'm hitting everybody right at somebody.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, well, you're hitting the ball too good.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's too good.
[SPEAKER_03]: The ball's coming too good to me.
[SPEAKER_03]: I didn't know anything about that.
[SPEAKER_03]: Jack Green was an unknown cricket counselor.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, yeah?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: He would choke up, I guess.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, Jack used to get either a two-base hit or a three-base hit.
[SPEAKER_03]: Then there was Charlie Jamison.
[SPEAKER_03]: He took Gramey's place.
[SPEAKER_04]: I guess it's their dad that used to say about Jamison, we grew up in Cleveland, you see, that's why I particularly interested in talking to you because I didn't see you play.
[SPEAKER_04]: I didn't follow the Indians up, but I knew something about their history.
[SPEAKER_04]: My father used to see them in their twenties in jeans, and he said we'd bunt the ball down the first baseline and keep it right between his legs.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was a great ballpark.
[SPEAKER_03]: 1966 in Lexington.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was a good ballpark.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know if the pitchers liked that right field wall too well.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, it was a great hitting ballpark.
[SPEAKER_03]: There was no signage or anything.
[SPEAKER_03]: Everything was green.
[SPEAKER_03]: Very good.
[SPEAKER_03]: No seats in center field.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was less centered, but you wouldn't lose the ball.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, it had a good background.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, I enjoyed it.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's right at the heart of a ghetto right now.
[SPEAKER_03]: I guess it is.
[SPEAKER_03]: I remember we used to go through Wade Park in those days.
[SPEAKER_03]: I guess you don't dare do that now.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is that where you stayed when you... No, no.
[SPEAKER_03]: I stayed on 55th and Lexington.
[SPEAKER_03]: There's a hotel there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Remember the old Pennsylvania?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: Right by it.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's changed, I guess.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I bet it has.
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you know George Ely?
[SPEAKER_03]: Very well.
[SPEAKER_03]: He lives in the Bay Village just outside Clayton.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think Womby lives in Lakewood.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, Lakewood.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's where I was born and raised.
[SPEAKER_04]: I actually interviewed Womby back in 1930s when I was writing for my junior high school newspaper.
[SPEAKER_04]: I didn't realize he was doing that.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, he's a very fine man.
[SPEAKER_04]: He really had a lot of good yearnings and badgers, he had armful of others.
[SPEAKER_04]: Went to Bonesetter Reefs all the time when I was young.
[SPEAKER_04]: He was a good hitter too.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, I think he was.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'm proud of his hitting and his pitching.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, he's very good.
[SPEAKER_03]: He used to pitch it quite a bit.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, that was nice.
[SPEAKER_03]: Jim Bagby, Kowalewski, and Ed Kletfer.
[SPEAKER_04]: You weren't with him, of course, in the World Series.
[SPEAKER_04]: No.
[SPEAKER_04]: You didn't see all those wild plays that happened then.
[SPEAKER_04]: No, I wasn't there.
[SPEAKER_04]: When Chapman got picked, too.
[SPEAKER_04]: Buoly said that Ray Caldwell got struck by lightning.
[SPEAKER_03]: Right.
[SPEAKER_04]: top of his cap, and you could see the sparks come out of his spikes.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, they tell that story.
[SPEAKER_03]: I've told it several times.
[SPEAKER_03]: People look at it, and they must be nuts.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I was right, because there's a rubber, see, out there, see?
[SPEAKER_03]: Sand on the rubber, and I guess it's a little metal.
[SPEAKER_03]: They used to have a little metal button on the top of your cap.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'm trying to think of even, oh, Fritz Kumbi was a left-hander.
[SPEAKER_03]: He lived out here, didn't he, down south?
[SPEAKER_03]: He's dead now.
[SPEAKER_03]: Fritz, I don't think he lived out here.
[SPEAKER_03]: I've got a directory of the carrier.
[SPEAKER_03]: I've got enough stuff for him to live.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'm trying to think of, yeah, another left-hander.
[SPEAKER_03]: Sherrod Smith.
[SPEAKER_03]: He had a move that wouldn't be allowed today, first base.
[SPEAKER_03]: The difference I find today is there's more stars on one club, whereas in the old days you'd be one, maybe one or two if you stood out.
[SPEAKER_03]: But this day, you find four or five on one ball club.
[SPEAKER_03]: And of course, the ball being more lively, I think, had a lot to do with it, too.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, I'll swing for the fancy now.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, that's what you do.
[SPEAKER_03]: Jameson.
[SPEAKER_03]: We had about, oh, 15 or 18 nephews right here.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, boy.
[SPEAKER_03]: And it's a beautiful town.
[SPEAKER_03]: I mean, this used to be nothing but an apple orchard.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's probably it.
[SPEAKER_03]: When I was a youngster, the population was about 2,000, but we never locked any doors or anything.
[SPEAKER_03]: Never.
[SPEAKER_03]: Times have changed.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's a nice town.
[SPEAKER_03]: Hm?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yes, it is.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's really nice.
[SPEAKER_04]: Any other pitchers you remember batting against?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, Herbert Shocker, Brett Faber.
[SPEAKER_03]: Bill Spitbar.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I can hit Spitbar.
[SPEAKER_03]: I broke in against Spitbar.
[SPEAKER_03]: Bill Steen.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, he was in Cleveland years ago when he was out.
[SPEAKER_03]: He finished up out there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Steen, Seaton, Krapp, Harkness.
[SPEAKER_03]: And that was a great pitcher.
[SPEAKER_03]: I mean, Portland's pitching staff, very, very good.
[SPEAKER_03]: Dean Gregg, he was a great pitcher.
[SPEAKER_04]: Was he on the way down then or the way up?
[SPEAKER_03]: He was on his way up.
[SPEAKER_03]: Then he went to Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_03]: Then there was Gus Fisher.
[SPEAKER_03]: He went to Cleveland, catcher.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think he went to Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_03]: Homer Hayworth.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you know Roger Peckinpah?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I met him.
[SPEAKER_03]: I didn't know him very well.
[SPEAKER_03]: He came over later on, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, he was a partner, too.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's right, he was very important.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, there was Olsen, Bancroft, Peckinpah, Rich Hartsfield, McCready.
[SPEAKER_04]: How did you like the umpires?
[SPEAKER_04]: Any of them stand out in your mind?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I liked them all.
[SPEAKER_03]: I killed the randoms from out here, you know, in San Francisco.
[SPEAKER_03]: Ben Conley, Evans, Rick Owens, Bill Guthrie.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh boy, he was a dandy.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'll never forget when I saw Link, he was umpiring out here, and I disputed his decision.
[SPEAKER_03]: I put my hand on my head and said, listen, Louie, remember this, the clothes of the umpire are as sacred as the robes of the Pope.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'll never forget it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, he was a good umpire too, an excellent umpire.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did he ever put you out of the game?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, he never put me out of the game.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's quite an achievement.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I had a lot of respect for umpires because that's a tough job.
[SPEAKER_03]: You can't please them all, you know.
[SPEAKER_03]: But this one in particular, I mean, it stuck out.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'll never forget it.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did a so-called black one come out here?
[SPEAKER_03]: He came out here.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, no, he was back there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Byron come out here.
[SPEAKER_03]: You should throw that indicator up all the time.
[SPEAKER_03]: You can't hit the ball with your bat on your shoulder.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a good umpire too.
[SPEAKER_03]: Sheridan?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, O'Day and Sheridan I think were through then.
[SPEAKER_04]: The Coast League, you have some of these playa umpires started out here that went up then, I guess, like Guthrie.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, Guthrie and Hildebrand, Pennelly, Dave Pennelly and a gentleman, Sonoma, Boy Springs.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is that very far from here?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, it's 12 miles, 12 miles.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, he was up there for, he was a good umpire.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was up there a good ball player, yes, he was.
[SPEAKER_04]: What was his real name, was that it?
[SPEAKER_04]: Polinelli.
[SPEAKER_04]: Took out a couple of syllables.
[SPEAKER_03]: Rinaldo Polinelli.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, that newspaper didn't do that, you know, they cut it up.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was too long for them.
[SPEAKER_04]: Wasn't there an old player named Asbjørnsson who became Asbie?
[SPEAKER_04]: Who?
[SPEAKER_04]: Somebody named Asbjørnsson, a Norwegian saying, I don't know who he played for, but somebody told me that story.
[SPEAKER_04]: He was up briefly, Asbjørnsson.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, did you have any humorous incidents you recall in the baseball field either?
[SPEAKER_04]: Not very many.
[SPEAKER_04]: Something funny seems to be happening all the time, crazy plays.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I saw one player, Mickey Cochran, made when he was in Portland.
[SPEAKER_03]: and the catcher was down to catch and receive the ball, he jumped over onto the plate.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was quite a feat.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I haven't seen very many of them.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, one of them came up to Salt Lake.
[SPEAKER_03]: We were going very badly.
[SPEAKER_03]: We were scoring runs.
[SPEAKER_03]: And what they did was pile up bats up in a tiki form, you know.
[SPEAKER_03]: gets a newspaper, put it on there, and started a fire.
[SPEAKER_04]: Any big thrills that stand out in your mind, baseball?
[SPEAKER_04]: Any big days?
[SPEAKER_04]: No.
[SPEAKER_04]: Great players?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, they were just kind of routine.
[SPEAKER_03]: I broke in my first baseball pitch, and luckily he hit it over the fence.
[SPEAKER_03]: He caught it in there?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: when I broke in.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's about the way I broke in.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, that's the way to break in.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I was kind of frail there.
[SPEAKER_03]: That wasn't Multnomah Park, was it?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, it was over in San Francisco.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_03]: See, that was one of the... See, we played over... Oakland played in San Francisco except Thursday and Sunday morning.
[SPEAKER_03]: I mean, San Francisco was a big one.
[SPEAKER_03]: And we'd play Sunday morning and we'd take the ferry and go over and play in the afternoon.
[SPEAKER_04]: Down in L.A., there were... Vernon had a team down there?
[SPEAKER_04]: Vernon, yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: And Hollywood didn't have... No, there was no Hollywood then.
[SPEAKER_03]: And L.A.?
[SPEAKER_03]: And the ballpark, as you were saying, was right there in town.
[SPEAKER_03]: I can't remember the street, Hill Street, I think.
[SPEAKER_03]: Was that through the Wrigley Park?
[SPEAKER_03]: Was that it?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_03]: Wrigley, oh, that's afterwards.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, this, when I played there, the ballpark was right in the center of town.
[SPEAKER_03]: That land would be, I couldn't buy it now, of course.
[SPEAKER_03]: Then over the left field fence, the television had, not a television, but the movie studios had a wild animal there that they used in their pictures, right over the left field fence.
[SPEAKER_03]: What did you do in the off-season?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well...
[SPEAKER_04]: Hunting?
[SPEAKER_03]: Fishing?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I did a lot of them.
[SPEAKER_03]: Fishing quite a bit.
[SPEAKER_03]: Climbing.
[SPEAKER_03]: I got things to do.
[SPEAKER_03]: There really wasn't anything to do.
[SPEAKER_03]: In the small town, everybody had a job.
[SPEAKER_04]: It wouldn't give you a job because you're going to be playing ball next year, is that it?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, it's a hobby of the pugs.
[SPEAKER_04]: If they wanted it anyway, it wasn't permanent.
[SPEAKER_04]: With your training, though, at school, you might have had some opportunities there.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you know Carl Mays?
[SPEAKER_04]: You didn't get to know him, did you?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, I used to know him.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I didn't know him.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was pitching at the time, though.
[SPEAKER_03]: Carl Mays was... At that time, when I knew him, he was at Boston Red Sox.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, they had a great pitching staff.
[SPEAKER_03]: Ruth and Mays.
[SPEAKER_03]: Ernie Shore.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, Gideon, Joe Wood.
[SPEAKER_03]: Joe Wood actually came to Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_03]: He lost his pitching arm.
[SPEAKER_04]: He lost his pitching arm.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: He dropped Ernie Shore down there in North Carolina, which is a perfect game, you know.
[SPEAKER_04]: But they had a great pitching staff, the Red Sox.
[SPEAKER_04]: Frazee showed them all.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, how about after baseball, what did you do?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I went...
[SPEAKER_03]: I coached at St. Mary's, coached baseball there for a number of years.
[SPEAKER_03]: Then I operated the student store, book store, you know, odds and ends.
[SPEAKER_03]: It got me pretty busy.
[SPEAKER_03]: Then I retired in about 1960.
[SPEAKER_04]: today.
[SPEAKER_04]: It was not scheduled, really.
[SPEAKER_04]: We spent last night at Lodi, which is about 110 miles away, I guess.
[SPEAKER_04]: Where?
[SPEAKER_04]: Petaluma?
[SPEAKER_00]: Petaluma.
[SPEAKER_04]: Petaluma, California.
[SPEAKER_04]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Petaluma.
[SPEAKER_04]: Petaluma.
[SPEAKER_00]: I put an N in it, I think.
[SPEAKER_04]: This is a little bit north of San Francisco, KOA campground here on Route 101 or something like it, on Saturday night, June 24th.
[SPEAKER_04]: We had this interview with Louis Guisto earlier today.
[SPEAKER_04]: It was not scheduled, really.
[SPEAKER_04]: We spent last night at Lodi, which is about 110 miles away, I guess.
[SPEAKER_04]: And we drove on over this morning on a lovely day.
[SPEAKER_04]: And we thought we'd try Napa, where Guisto lives.
[SPEAKER_04]: And if not Napa, then up to Boys Springs, where Penelli lives, or Glen Ellyn, where Mark Koenig lives.
[SPEAKER_04]: Then we thought we'd maybe
[SPEAKER_04]: come over here after that, or else come over here before that and go back and make the interviews later.
[SPEAKER_04]: We weren't quite sure what the plan would be.
[SPEAKER_04]: But we got into Napa, got out to Guisto's house about quarter of 11, and he wasn't there.
[SPEAKER_04]: The garage was empty, and the spray was going in the front lawn.
[SPEAKER_04]: I went up and knocked on the door.
[SPEAKER_04]: No answer.
[SPEAKER_04]: A gentleman from across the street came over and said that he saw we were from West Virginia, and he wanted to make sure we
[SPEAKER_04]: knew what the story was, so he said Guisto had gone out shortly before and should be back very soon.
[SPEAKER_04]: Even though he was in his 80s, he was in good shape physically and would be disappointed if we hadn't seen him.
[SPEAKER_04]: I don't know about that.
[SPEAKER_04]: So we thought about it.
[SPEAKER_04]: Then we went into town and got something to eat.
[SPEAKER_04]: We hadn't eaten much.
[SPEAKER_04]: We went into the butternut dairy, butterflower bakery, I guess it was.
[SPEAKER_04]: Had some coffee and donuts.
[SPEAKER_04]: Then came back out, and it was about 11.30 now.
[SPEAKER_04]: And I talked to somebody else who said he should be back.
[SPEAKER_04]: We waited out in the car.
[SPEAKER_04]: We were going to leave after about 10 minutes.
[SPEAKER_04]: But he pulled in about then.
[SPEAKER_04]: And the gentleman next door came rushing out to tell him that there were some visitors from West Virginia, which didn't seem to thrill him greatly.
[SPEAKER_04]: But he acknowledged us and invited us in.
[SPEAKER_04]: And he was kind of rushed.
[SPEAKER_04]: He's a very ill sister, and he had other things to do.
[SPEAKER_04]: But he could give us a little bit of time.
[SPEAKER_04]: So we sat down there about 11.30 and had the half-hour tape, the other side of this tape.
[SPEAKER_04]: It wasn't much to it, but at least I talked to him and I heard him.
[SPEAKER_04]: He signed the ball, and we got a couple pictures.
[SPEAKER_04]: Now, could you describe the house?
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a stone house with a little porch-like affair coming out in front, a veranda-type thing that was covered with ivy that was thicker than your arm, the stalks.
[SPEAKER_04]: You said you could take off the porch pillars and the ivy stalks would hold up the roof.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And inside the house was very nicely furnished, actually.
[SPEAKER_00]: not modern by any means, but traditional furniture and pictures all over of nieces and nephews.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think he has 15 nephews living in Napa alone.
[SPEAKER_00]: In the dining room, it was a traditional dining room thing with a lace tablecloth on it, a plastic tablecloth on top of that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the sideboard or the buffet was loaded with liquor bottles.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so were all the ashtrays loaded with
[SPEAKER_00]: They had all been used.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then that little kitchen or den, whatever it was, was piled high with papers and books.
[SPEAKER_00]: It looked like your type of journal, whatever was in it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Maybe it does bookkeeping on the side or something.
[SPEAKER_04]: A little bit of clutter out there in the back rooms.
[SPEAKER_00]: But not in the living room.
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was except for the pictures, which were all over Kingdom Come.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course, they must be Catholic, because they had the
[SPEAKER_00]: Madonna and child up there in a crucifix.
[SPEAKER_00]: And has no children of his own.
[SPEAKER_00]: Whether he was married or not, we never did find out.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he has a, we know one younger sister and one older sister.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the younger sister has six grandchildren or something.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's when he said he had 15 to 18 nephews in the valley in Napa world.
[SPEAKER_04]: The front of the house is covered with bushes and trees and shrubbery.
[SPEAKER_04]: You could hardly see the house.
[SPEAKER_04]: And I walked around the back where this other gentleman spoke to me, and he had looked rather cluttered in back with bushes and trees.
[SPEAKER_04]: I didn't see any lawn or anything.
[SPEAKER_04]: Maybe he's got an orchard and some vines of his own out there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's a very good health for his age.
[SPEAKER_04]: He didn't look 83.
[SPEAKER_04]: Little hunched over, very stout, he always was stout.
[SPEAKER_04]: Gray-haired, rather firm features and a firm manner.
[SPEAKER_04]: I remember his pictures back in the 20s with the mustache.
[SPEAKER_04]: He seemed so unusual wearing a mustache then.
[SPEAKER_04]: I think I did.
[SPEAKER_04]: He didn't have one now.
[SPEAKER_04]: But he still was recognizable, though, as I recall those old pictures.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he didn't even tell any good stories after we left.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, after the tape went off.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I think he was surprised that you left as soon as it switched off.
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh, you do?
[SPEAKER_04]: Why?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just got that impression that he was surprised you were ready to leave.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, I felt that he wanted me to leave.
[SPEAKER_04]: It was kind of an imposition coming in like that.
[SPEAKER_04]: And I said, do you have some time?
[SPEAKER_04]: He said, well, a few minutes.
[SPEAKER_04]: And I said, well, he said, how much time?
[SPEAKER_04]: I said, maybe an hour.
[SPEAKER_04]: And he looked at his watch and said, well, just an hour.
[SPEAKER_04]: So from that crew, I felt imposed to take a half an hour.
[SPEAKER_04]: I didn't think he was unhappy to quit then.
[SPEAKER_04]: The living room was dark.
[SPEAKER_04]: There were no lights on in there.
[SPEAKER_04]: I thought we might take some.
[SPEAKER_04]: We did take a couple pictures.
[SPEAKER_04]: I hope they came out, but there wasn't much.
[SPEAKER_04]: It was kind of gloomy in a way.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he didn't have any pictures of himself.
[SPEAKER_04]: He just had one of those cut-out postboard ones.
[SPEAKER_00]: When he played at Oakland?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, it was standing up, which was over in the mantelpiece.
[SPEAKER_04]: That was all he had.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, he wasn't up that long, was he?
[SPEAKER_04]: No, he played quite a few years in the Coast League, though.
[SPEAKER_04]: He had his career ran over 10 or 12 years.
[SPEAKER_04]: But he was lost some time in the war.
[SPEAKER_04]: I guess I had heard that.
[SPEAKER_04]: He'd been gassed in the war, and this really affected his career.
[SPEAKER_04]: Then he had a couple of injuries, too, at the time.
[SPEAKER_04]: Somebody ran into him there and broke his hand.
[SPEAKER_04]: So he had some misfortunes, which certainly affected his career.
[SPEAKER_04]: Didn't, I don't know, didn't seem to have too much of a sense of humor.
[SPEAKER_04]: I don't know that I expected this, but it was pretty cut and dry, the whole business.
[SPEAKER_04]: So I didn't really have any desire to drag it out much longer.
[SPEAKER_04]: Covered the ground as best we could in half an hour.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's probably the longest interview he's ever had, I suppose.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's about the shortest one I've had.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I think we've covered the ground on him.
[SPEAKER_04]: We've got about 20 minutes to go on this side.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, after we left him, it was around 12, 15 or so, we drove into Sonoma.
[SPEAKER_04]: which was Thornton Lee's hometown, whom we interviewed a couple of days ago.
[SPEAKER_04]: No, a couple of weeks ago, I guess, before Palm Springs.
[SPEAKER_04]: And we found Sonoma a very attractive town, quite historic, a plaza that looked like a real Spanish laid-out town, much like Santa Fe had been, with these low-story buildings circumventing the square.
[SPEAKER_04]: Some historic buildings.
[SPEAKER_04]: They have the monument where the Bear Flag Republic was raised back in 1846, announcing the independence of California, which was probably repudiated by the United States.
[SPEAKER_04]: For a brief month or so, there was an independent state of California.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's on the square.
[SPEAKER_04]: The home of Yeho, and I never knew who he was.
[SPEAKER_00]: The founders didn't know him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was the one who was governor, or whoever, whatever it was, when they raised the bear flag.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the mission there is the northernmost mission in the mission trail.
[SPEAKER_04]: That would have been nice to see that mission.
[SPEAKER_04]: I'm sorry we didn't.
[SPEAKER_04]: But what happened was we got a little concerned about a place to stay.
[SPEAKER_04]: And the other interviews, I tried to call Babe Pennelly and got all kinds of a run around there.
[SPEAKER_04]: Never could find him.
[SPEAKER_04]: It was along about 2 o'clock.
[SPEAKER_04]: We decided to find a place to stay and then maybe see Sonora better, or completely.
[SPEAKER_04]: They had a winery we wanted to go through.
[SPEAKER_04]: But the one motel in town was taken, so we drove over here.
[SPEAKER_04]: By the time we got here, we got all set up.
[SPEAKER_04]: We just didn't feel like going back there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Everything would have been closed in.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, well, we might have barely made it, but there probably would have been time for a tour of the winery.
[SPEAKER_04]: And I don't know what else we could have seen.
[SPEAKER_04]: So we probably should have done something else, but that's the way it worked out.
[SPEAKER_04]: We didn't get the Penelli interview.
[SPEAKER_04]: Mark Koenig, he's got his name in the phone book, but I don't know that we'll be able to see him.
[SPEAKER_04]: We've got to get going home one of these days, and I think we're going to start tomorrow as we go farther north and west.
[SPEAKER_04]: We keep getting farther away from home as we go home.
[SPEAKER_04]: But we've got to go farther away to start back.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's the only way we can do it.
[SPEAKER_04]: So I guess that's about it on the Louis Guisto interview.
[SPEAKER_04]: It wasn't the greatest interview, but it did satisfy a desire I'd long had to meet Louis Guisto.
[SPEAKER_04]: Anything else?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_04]: Tomorrow it's on the road up north.
[SPEAKER_04]: And maybe we'll have a great interview with Joe Oscar, who's probably 88.
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh, God.
[SPEAKER_04]: In Ferndale.
[SPEAKER_04]: But he pitched in that long game.
[SPEAKER_04]: We'll see.
[SPEAKER_04]: But that's all for this time.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, that's a good while back.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: When was it?
[SPEAKER_04]: You mean professionally?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: Minor leagues first.
[SPEAKER_02]: Minor leagues?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I broke in in 1914 in minor league.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then I played there for... Where'd you play?
[SPEAKER_02]: An old Central League.
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh yeah?
[SPEAKER_04]: Not far from here, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, just right over here at Springfield.
[SPEAKER_02]: Dayton, Springfield, Wheeling, Evansville, they were in that league then.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then I went from there up to, well I didn't break in there, I upgraded up at Saginaw, the old Southern Michigan League.
[SPEAKER_02]: Ducky Holmes, he was
[SPEAKER_02]: the manager of the Saginaw team.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I went up there with him.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then after that, after they quit up there, I went over to Detroit.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I belonged to Detroit for a couple of years, and they sent me over to Springfield over in the old Central League.
[SPEAKER_04]: And... Did you play under Huey Jennings up there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_04]: How'd you like Huey Jennings?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_02]: Very tough manager?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, he didn't have nothing much to say to me.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was just a youngster, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: What'd Ty Cobb tell you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I'll tell you what.
[SPEAKER_02]: Ty Cobb told me one day I was pitching bat and practicing.
[SPEAKER_02]: After I finished, I just happened to finish with him, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: And he walked over to me and he said, kid, he said,
[SPEAKER_02]: you've got a good fastball, you're pretty hard to follow."
[SPEAKER_02]: And he said, someday they'll be reading about you.
[SPEAKER_02]: So you see, you never can tell.
[SPEAKER_04]: He was right, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Then I spent a couple years in the old Hunter League over at Springfield.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then finally I drifted off and went out in the Western League.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was out there a couple of years.
[SPEAKER_02]: In 19... Out in Denver, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Denver.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then I came back to Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was with Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_02]: I pitched one game down here at Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they left me go, and then I went up to the Steel League up at Mashland.
[SPEAKER_02]: And in 1919, I went back out in the Western League.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's been so long ago.
[SPEAKER_04]: I have your record here.
[SPEAKER_04]: Do you?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, that was 1919, Kansas City and Tulsa.
[SPEAKER_04]: Kansas City, yes.
[SPEAKER_04]: Real good year, 21 and 5.
[SPEAKER_04]: 21 and 5.
[SPEAKER_02]: I started to pitch for Kansas City on the second day of July.
[SPEAKER_02]: I pitched my first game for them.
[SPEAKER_02]: Second day of July, and I pitched 21 games.
[SPEAKER_04]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_04]: Every third day almost.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I won 21 for them.
[SPEAKER_02]: 21 out of 26.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then the Cardinals bought you, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: And Ricky came out there.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he went up in the office and
[SPEAKER_02]: Mr. Muellenbeck then owned a Kansas City club, and he said, Mr. Muellenbeck, he said, you want to sell this fellow Haynes?
[SPEAKER_02]: And he said, yes, I'll sell him.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, how much do you want for him?
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, $10,000.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, I'll take him.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I went to the, that's the way I got into the big leagues.
[SPEAKER_02]: I always give Ricky credit for giving me a chance for the majors because they bought me and paid for me and had to scrape and scrape.
[SPEAKER_02]: St. Louis didn't have any money.
[SPEAKER_02]: He came and told me one time coming riding on the railroad or train coming back from New York, I think it was.
[SPEAKER_02]: or going to New York, he said, I didn't have $10,000.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, I didn't know where I was going to get $10,000.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he said, I came back from St. Louis or Kansas City to borrow $10,000 to pay for you, and nobody would even give me $10,000.
[SPEAKER_02]: So he said, and that's the way Braden came into the picture then out there in St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_04]: Were there any other clubs after you with that good year?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, there were several clubs out there, but Ricky beat them to me.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, you start in right away with some good years there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I didn't have a very good year in the first year.
[SPEAKER_02]: We had a terrible ball club.
[SPEAKER_04]: Who was on it that first year?
[SPEAKER_04]: Do you remember anybody?
[SPEAKER_02]: We had Fournier.
[SPEAKER_02]: Here's your first basement?
[SPEAKER_02]: First basement.
[SPEAKER_02]: Orangeby was the second.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, that's a pretty good second basement.
[SPEAKER_02]: Levan, Johnny Levan was the shortstop.
[SPEAKER_02]: Milton Stock, third base.
[SPEAKER_02]: Jack Smith, now at Field.
[SPEAKER_02]: I just don't know who the other fellows were, but we was kind of a ball club.
[SPEAKER_02]: We made enough runs, but we'd give the fellows more than we could make.
[SPEAKER_04]: Who were some other pitchers?
[SPEAKER_04]: Do you remember any other pitchers?
[SPEAKER_02]: With us?
[SPEAKER_04]: Bill Doak.
[SPEAKER_04]: Was he the spitballer?
[SPEAKER_02]: Marvin Goodwin was a spitter too.
[SPEAKER_02]: Billy Sherdell.
[SPEAKER_02]: Wee Willie.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know some of the rest of them?
[SPEAKER_02]: He was with me.
[SPEAKER_04]: You married then, were you?
[SPEAKER_04]: You married a minor league ball player who made the hall of fame, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: But it was a...
[SPEAKER_02]: I had a bad year the first year, but then I started to go on and I went pretty good for a couple of years, and then I had another bad year.
[SPEAKER_02]: And things started going pretty good from then on.
[SPEAKER_02]: But we had a good ball club.
[SPEAKER_02]: We started getting together a good ball club.
[SPEAKER_04]: What was Hornsby like to play behind you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, he was all right.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did he ride you much?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was the kind of a fellow that Hornsby knew what you could do almost and he'd never say anything to you.
[SPEAKER_02]: But as long as
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you mention Alexander?
[SPEAKER_04]: I was going to ask him about that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Alexander.
[SPEAKER_04]: He came on a little later.
[SPEAKER_02]: He came on in 1925.
[SPEAKER_02]: He came over from Chicago in 1925, him and Baldwin Farrell.
[SPEAKER_04]: Farrell was the most valuable player in the league that, or was it the next year I guess?
[SPEAKER_04]: 26.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, you achieved another great distinction in 1924.
[SPEAKER_02]: No hit game.
[SPEAKER_04]: How'd that feel?
[SPEAKER_04]: Tell me a little bit about that game.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I remember that very well.
[SPEAKER_02]: Casey Stengel was the last fellow I got out.
[SPEAKER_01]: Really?
[SPEAKER_02]: Casey Stengel.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did that game go?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you feel real good that whole game?
[SPEAKER_01]: Were there any near hits or anything like that?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I felt pretty good that whole ball game.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was a day out there that they had a reserve for the Tuberculosis Association.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they sell it out to that association and they handle it all, see.
[SPEAKER_02]: It just happened to be on that day.
[SPEAKER_04]: Pretty big crowd then, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: For that time, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you strike out a lot of batters that day?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I never struck out so many.
[SPEAKER_02]: What was your best pitch?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I just hit the fastball on the curve and changed the pace.
[SPEAKER_04]: And that day they were all working.
[SPEAKER_02]: Not then.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_01]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_01]: You never get them.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, they were all working that day, though, the ones you had, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: They were all working pretty good.
[SPEAKER_04]: What were your feelings in that last inning or so?
[SPEAKER_04]: You knew you had a no-hitter going?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I knew it, yes.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I kept bearing down.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did it make you nervous at all?
[SPEAKER_04]: Or didn't you get nervous out there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I couldn't say that it did.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did the team tell you much about it, or did they talk much on the bench that you had a no-hitter going, or didn't they talk about things like that?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_04]: They all knew it, though?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I presume yes.
[SPEAKER_02]: Of course, that's been a long time ago.
[SPEAKER_04]: What did Stengel do?
[SPEAKER_04]: Did he do anything his last at bat?
[SPEAKER_04]: Did he do much or just... Who?
[SPEAKER_04]: Casey.
[SPEAKER_04]: How'd you get Casey out for the last man?
[SPEAKER_04]: I don't remember that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I just pitched to him just like I always did and hit a nice ground ball down to Hornsby at second base.
[SPEAKER_02]: And that was it.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did they rush out to greet you at all?
[SPEAKER_04]: I guess they did.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you see that game?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh, you can tell us about it.
[SPEAKER_04]: She can tell you more about it than I can.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I just think it was rather the wives were sitting together, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: And especially my one friend that was Mr. Well, anyway, it was eighth inning.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the lady's name was Ethel.
[SPEAKER_01]: And she said, she heard somebody say behind her, she said, well, he hasn't given up a hit yet.
[SPEAKER_01]: And so she asked me whether there was
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't know whether to say yes or no, because I thought I didn't want to say anything, because I never said anything when the ball game was going on.
[SPEAKER_01]: Especially when Jess was pitching, I never would say a word.
[SPEAKER_01]: And she asked me, and I said yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: So far, he has no hit game.
[SPEAKER_01]: And of course, I was very, very nervous.
[SPEAKER_00]: Too bad.
[SPEAKER_00]: Probably more nervous than he was.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he came through and they just couldn't, the other way around, they didn't know it.
[SPEAKER_01]: They just couldn't believe it, you know, that he'd gone that far.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I was terribly uptight.
[SPEAKER_01]: They say be uptight, but I sure was uptight.
[SPEAKER_04]: How did he seem after the game?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, the 1926 World Series then, that was a great series, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, that was a great series.
[SPEAKER_01]: So you won, you pitched two complete games then, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: I beat him out in St. Louis 4-0.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then I started the 7th game in New York and that's when Illich relieved me and he won the game 3-2.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was ahead 3-2 when I went out.
[SPEAKER_04]: Was that the time he struck out Lazari?
[SPEAKER_02]: He struck out Rosario.
[SPEAKER_04]: Now, what's the story?
[SPEAKER_04]: Was he out all night the night before, living it up?
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, I wouldn't want to answer that because I don't know.
[SPEAKER_04]: That was the story, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_04]: He didn't expect to pitch that day.
[SPEAKER_02]: He never did go out all night, and I don't think he was out all night.
[SPEAKER_04]: But he wasn't expecting to pitch, I guess.
[SPEAKER_04]: He pitched the day before, was that it?
[SPEAKER_02]: He pitched the day before and beat them 7 to 2.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then I started the next day and was ahead of them three to two in the seventh.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then they got the bases full and two out.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they're like, Hornsby took me out and brought him in.
[SPEAKER_04]: What did Hornsby say?
[SPEAKER_04]: Do you remember when he took you out?
[SPEAKER_04]: Did he say anything?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I wore all the skin off my fingers here.
[SPEAKER_02]: Of course, I was throwing the knuckle then.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he took me out and brought in Illick.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he wasn't in too bad of shape.
[SPEAKER_02]: Ellick was a kind of a fellow that he kept all his everything to himself.
[SPEAKER_02]: If he wanted to go get a few drinks, he'd get them and then go away, go to himself.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he never caused anybody any trouble.
[SPEAKER_02]: All this stuff you read in the papers about him, like this bush war, a lot of it,
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell them about the time they said that, about him, you know, that he was out here working on the railroad or something.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, yes.
[SPEAKER_02]: After I was out of baseball, I was elected to office down here.
[SPEAKER_02]: And one day, they called me up from over to the paper, sports writer, and said that Jess said
[SPEAKER_02]: Ellick's on the railroad gang over there, cooking for the railroad gang.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I don't believe it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he's over there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was over there this morning.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, I don't care whether you was over there or who was over there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Ellick's no cook.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, would you ride over with me?
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, I sure will.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, well, I'll pick you up.
[SPEAKER_02]: So he drove through the alley and picked me up and we drove over.
[SPEAKER_02]: Railroad gang, you know, they got two or three cars along the railroad where they sleep and cook and eat and so forth.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I said, I'm going to drive down along the railroad here and stop.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'll holler for him to come to the window.
[SPEAKER_02]: And you can see whether it's Ellick or not.
[SPEAKER_02]: It won't be Ellick, I know that.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, you get him to that window, I'll tell you whether it's Ellick or not, and then I'll come over.
[SPEAKER_02]: So he called and drove over, and he stopped and hollered, Ellick!
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, Ellick!
[SPEAKER_02]: The fellow come up to the window and to the door, you know, he's got a door, a car door.
[SPEAKER_02]: started talking.
[SPEAKER_02]: I got out of the door and got out of the car and walked over and there he stood.
[SPEAKER_02]: And you know what, the sucker just called me right by name.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I said to him, now look,
[SPEAKER_02]: You're just an imposter, that's all you are.
[SPEAKER_02]: You're no more Alexander than I'm Alexander."
[SPEAKER_02]: And I said, you know what he was doing?
[SPEAKER_02]: They were bringing baseballs there for him to sign for a dollar a piece.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he was signing Alex's name.
[SPEAKER_02]: I told the, and the press down here was there with, you know, he was there.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he said, I know it wasn't Alexander, but he said, I want to make sure.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I said, well, I said, you know it isn't Millick.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, he said, I know it isn't Millick.
[SPEAKER_02]: So he said, well, he said, I'll tell you what.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, I'll go back in a couple of days and see if he's still there.
[SPEAKER_02]: So it was about three or four days, and I got a call from up at Osgoode up here, same guy.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they said that Jess,
[SPEAKER_02]: You know Alexander's up here cooking for a gang?"
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, no, that's not Alexander.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, you'd better just tell him to get out of there.
[SPEAKER_02]: As soon as I can see the commissioner, I'm going to get him.
[SPEAKER_02]: But that's the last I ever heard of him.
[SPEAKER_02]: So when I went up to
[SPEAKER_01]: Where did we go?
[SPEAKER_02]: I saw the commissioner and I told him about it.
[SPEAKER_02]: He says if I ever hear of him, I'll take care of him.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I don't think they ever heard any more about him.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was signing the baseballs, you know.
[SPEAKER_04]: When would this have been?
[SPEAKER_04]: The late 1930s or so?
[SPEAKER_02]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_04]: When would this have been?
[SPEAKER_04]: After you were out of baseball, late 30s or 40s maybe?
[SPEAKER_02]: It must have been in the 40s.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was down in the office.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was in there seven years, seven terms.
[SPEAKER_02]: It must have been around the first couple of terms I was down there.
[SPEAKER_04]: What was it like pitching to Babe Ruth?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I'll tell you, he was a wonderful hitter.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a great hitter, there was no question about that.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I pitched to him just like I'd pitch to anybody else.
[SPEAKER_04]: That shutout you pitched, did you get him out pretty well that time?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: How about Gehrig?
[SPEAKER_02]: They got four hits off of me, I think, in that game.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know who got them anymore.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were a team.
[SPEAKER_01]: Boy, they were a team.
[SPEAKER_04]: The Yankees, I know.
[SPEAKER_04]: That was Murderer's Row, all right.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I don't think that...
[SPEAKER_02]: I see that the commissioners told them to play Aaron at Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know whether they will or not.
[SPEAKER_00]: Maybe he won't get hit on purpose down there.
[SPEAKER_04]: Why'd they trade Hornsby for Frisch?
[SPEAKER_02]: Why did they?
[SPEAKER_04]: Did Hornsby get in a fight with Breeden, was that it, or Rickey?
[SPEAKER_04]: Do you remember that at all?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, Rickey wasn't there then.
[SPEAKER_04]: He must have gotten a...
[SPEAKER_04]: He had a great year, I guess, and then...
[SPEAKER_04]: I think they got into it, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I never did hear why they made that trade.
[SPEAKER_02]: Braden?
[SPEAKER_04]: It was a pretty even up trade I guess.
[SPEAKER_04]: Would you say Hornsby is better than Frisch?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I'll tell you.
[SPEAKER_02]: I wouldn't put that, turn my hand for the difference.
[SPEAKER_02]: Fish was a good ball player.
[SPEAKER_02]: And so was Hornbury.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you see many of the old ball players?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, we haven't been able to go down to Savannah.
[SPEAKER_01]: This hasn't been well enough in the last few years.
[SPEAKER_01]: But we went down there, though, quite often.
[SPEAKER_04]: What was your best year?
[SPEAKER_04]: 27.
[SPEAKER_04]: That was the year you didn't win the Penentho.
[SPEAKER_02]: 24 and lost 10.
[SPEAKER_04]: And they didn't win the Penentho that year, huh?
[SPEAKER_04]: No.
[SPEAKER_04]: Where'd you finish?
[SPEAKER_04]: Second?
[SPEAKER_04]: Right.
[SPEAKER_04]: How'd the team do in 27?
[SPEAKER_02]: They won second, I think.
[SPEAKER_02]: The Pirates beat you out, huh?
[SPEAKER_04]: And what was your team that year?
[SPEAKER_04]: Who were the Cardinals?
[SPEAKER_04]: What was the line-up of the team?
[SPEAKER_04]: What was the Cardinals line-up in those 26, 27, 28, those years when they won two pennants?
[SPEAKER_02]: Bottomley?
[SPEAKER_04]: No, Bottomley.
[SPEAKER_04]: With Sparky Adams in that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he in that?
[SPEAKER_04]: He was playing shortstop for us.
[SPEAKER_01]: In what year?
[SPEAKER_02]: 26, 27, 28.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you have DeRocher for a brief time?
[SPEAKER_02]: I was thinking that DeRocher was in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, he was.
[SPEAKER_01]: DeRocher.
[SPEAKER_01]: He played a couple of years.
[SPEAKER_02]: 30, 29, 30.
[SPEAKER_02]: We had good bull cubs in there, too.
[SPEAKER_02]: 31.
[SPEAKER_04]: How about Pepper Martin?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, he was...
[SPEAKER_04]: He livened the team up, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, he was something.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was good.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't care how... You know, most of those fellas are dead.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was going to make it, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, the Rocher's around.
[SPEAKER_04]: He's still here.
[SPEAKER_04]: Joe Medwick, he came a little later, though.
[SPEAKER_02]: Medwick, we had Medwick.
[SPEAKER_04]: Taylor Douthat, is he?
[SPEAKER_02]: Douthat was here.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's still living.
[SPEAKER_04]: He's out west, I guess, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: He's out in Oakland.
[SPEAKER_04]: He had Ernie Orsatti.
[SPEAKER_04]: I guess he wasn't regular though, was he?
[SPEAKER_04]: The gas house gang, is that really a rough crew?
[SPEAKER_04]: No, they just called them that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Nice bunch of boys.
[SPEAKER_04]: Who was your catcher?
[SPEAKER_02]: Jimmy Wilson?
[SPEAKER_02]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_02]: O'Farrell?
[SPEAKER_02]: Mancuso?
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, Mancuso, I think, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Gonzales caught me by the way he gave.
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh, is that right?
[SPEAKER_04]: Mike, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: She had a little boy, Miss Comptailers, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: She doesn't have him yet.
[SPEAKER_01]: Often wonder, you know, about the little ones that walk around in there, what they're doing and everything.
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course, he was much, well, quite a bit older than his wife, you know, Comptailers.
[SPEAKER_02]: too much money today.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, they don't play ball because they like it much anymore.
[SPEAKER_02]: They play for the money.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you ever have any whole contract disputes with breeding and all?
[SPEAKER_02]: Only one time I had a little bit, but not much anything.
[SPEAKER_04]: What'd you do in the off-seasons in those years?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I... Go hunting?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, we had a garage, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: He'd go and he'd work in the garage some in the wintertime.
[SPEAKER_02]: You owned the garage?
[SPEAKER_02]: Mm-hmm.
[SPEAKER_01]: The building.
[SPEAKER_02]: Owned a garage up here on the corner and had that.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's still up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's still up there, but it's not a garage.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's another compound.
[SPEAKER_02]: They got some other kind of a business in it now that they make plates for...
[SPEAKER_01]: It's called Come Do It.
[SPEAKER_01]: They come do it now, but if that is...
[SPEAKER_02]: Connections for televisions, those little wires, you know.
[SPEAKER_02]: Fellow's doing real good, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was all in that one?
[SPEAKER_01]: I built it in 1921.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you run it during the summer season?
[SPEAKER_04]: Did somebody run it for you?
[SPEAKER_01]: His brother.
[SPEAKER_04]: Your brother ran it during the baseball season?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: You grew up right here?
[SPEAKER_04]: You were born in Phillipsburg?
[SPEAKER_02]: I was born three miles down the road here.
[SPEAKER_04]: What did your father do?
[SPEAKER_02]: My father?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he was a real estate auctioneer, sales,
[SPEAKER_02]: country sales, farm sales, and he was a... drove a lot of nails in the summertime.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a carpenter.
[SPEAKER_04]: What do you think of your going into baseball?
[SPEAKER_04]: Did he like it or not like it?
[SPEAKER_04]: Or didn't he?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he didn't seem to think too much of it at first, but after I got started, I said, well, I guess it looks like he was born to do that, so...
[SPEAKER_01]: His mother said he's always been throwing stones, always throwing them.
[SPEAKER_01]: He gets them.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got a place, wasn't it a pole?
[SPEAKER_01]: A black tile.
[SPEAKER_01]: Telephone poles, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: We still have telephone poles here.
[SPEAKER_01]: And telephone poles, and his mother, not his mother, told me, said,
[SPEAKER_01]: He'd just go out by himself and he'd just keep going to one place, throwing stones.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's how his control developed, huh?
[SPEAKER_04]: Never had any control problems, huh?
[SPEAKER_04]: No control problems?
[SPEAKER_04]: Not much.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you always want to be a ball player?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you go to high school, play in the high school team?
[SPEAKER_02]: I had my arm broke.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was a right-handed pitcher.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I went to a ball game one Sunday afternoon right over here, right back over there.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I was about six years old.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't go to a ball game.
[SPEAKER_02]: I went up there to break my arm.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I broke my arm off right there.
[SPEAKER_02]: It just hung down like that.
[SPEAKER_02]: My dad was over to the ballgame.
[SPEAKER_02]: And somebody went over there and told him.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he come over and picked me up and carried me down to the doctor down here.
[SPEAKER_02]: And the doctor laid me down there on that old sofa of his.
[SPEAKER_02]: The springs was all up through it.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I remember that just as well as it had been yesterday.
[SPEAKER_02]: He laid me down on that and they went out in the shed and got a couple of shingles and brought them in and broke them off.
[SPEAKER_02]: Put him in here, up along there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then he got up on that sofa and got a hold of my arm.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he pulled it, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: Pulled it back in place.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they put those shingles on here, like this, on the side, outside here, see, like that.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they took and wrapped gauze around it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Wrapped up the gauze all around it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Dad took me home.
[SPEAKER_02]: About a week or ten days, my mother took me back down there.
[SPEAKER_02]: She told the doctor, because you're getting bowed down here, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: Underneath.
[SPEAKER_02]: She told the doctor, she said, doctor, don't you think you ought to have one of those splints on the bottom of that?
[SPEAKER_02]: Keep that straight.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, well, remember where we had better put one on there.
[SPEAKER_02]: So he put one on the bottom there, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: Wrapped it, straightened it all up.
[SPEAKER_02]: And the arm's crooked, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: So after I got all right and I got to throwing with it, I got to throwing a curve and the arm was crooked, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: And everybody said the reason I could throw a curve was my arm was crooked.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, my.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was that Dr. Brown?
[SPEAKER_02]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Was it Dr. Brown?
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he the dentist there?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, old Doc E. Spindler.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course, I didn't even know about it, but that was nice.
[SPEAKER_01]: I knew there was a Dr. Brown there one time when I was a girl.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did they have a high school team here you played on?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_04]: We didn't have no high school.
[SPEAKER_01]: They just said, just take anybody, you know.
[SPEAKER_04]: Who first scouted you?
[SPEAKER_04]: Who first picked you up, do you remember?
[SPEAKER_04]: Or who assigned you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, we had two teams here in town, around here in the country.
[SPEAKER_02]: We called them the big team and the little team.
[SPEAKER_02]: And we played
[SPEAKER_02]: the big team and play the teams around, and we had towns around here, you see, and they'd go every Sunday to one of those towns and play, until finally I grew into the big team.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I
[SPEAKER_02]: I got into Dayton.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was pitching a game one day, one Sunday afternoon, and some fellas come up from Dayton.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know who they were.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they asked me to come into Dayton the next Sunday, see.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I went in.
[SPEAKER_02]: I went into Dayton and I played for a team down there called Standards.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was in 1911.
[SPEAKER_02]: And in 1912, I played for the NCR team out at the old soldier's home.
[SPEAKER_02]: We called it the old soldier's home then.
[SPEAKER_04]: In Dayton?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: And in 1913, I played for
[SPEAKER_02]: Lula Bruce, team called Lula Bruce down there.
[SPEAKER_02]: And in 1914, then I went out and played.
[SPEAKER_04]: Some of you got signed that winter?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: To play with the Dayton professional team?
[SPEAKER_02]: Went up to Saginaw, Michigan.
[SPEAKER_04]: What was it like in the minor leagues in those days?
[SPEAKER_04]: Good food, good travel, good living conditions?
[SPEAKER_04]: Travel around by bus, did you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Gosh, I don't know how we did travel around anymore.
[SPEAKER_02]: Travel around the best you could.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think you went by train.
[SPEAKER_02]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: And you was up there in Detroit.
[SPEAKER_01]: Or Saginaw, I mean.
[SPEAKER_01]: You went through Detroit.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wasn't really there yet.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I'm sure you did, just by train.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because there's another way to go.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did they put you up in good hotels, in the minor leagues, or rooming houses?
[SPEAKER_02]: Any place they could put you up.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was just at Spokes Bread one time, up there, when he was playing up at Saginaw.
[SPEAKER_01]: And so she said his dad and mother went, and so they took me too.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we went by
[SPEAKER_01]: You went by train or else a streetcar for get rich.
[SPEAKER_01]: Or in the urban.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had them at that time.
[SPEAKER_01]: They might have been in the urban instead of...
[SPEAKER_02]: Even in the big league, we used to go on the road.
[SPEAKER_01]: We'd go on the road for 15 or 20 days and they'd give us $3.50 a day to eat on.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they'd come around
[SPEAKER_02]: Give us the money, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, if you ate that all up before you got home, it's too bad for you.
[SPEAKER_04]: Was that enough for you?
[SPEAKER_04]: Three and a half a day, you think?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: It wasn't?
[SPEAKER_02]: But you had to get along on that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, some of the hotels, the family hotel, we'd go in and sit down and eat, see?
[SPEAKER_02]: The old hotel over at Philadelphia, what they call it, the Aldine.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think it was the Aldine Hotel.
[SPEAKER_02]: We'd eat there, see, family hotel.
[SPEAKER_02]: But most of them, they just give you the money and you go and eat.
[SPEAKER_02]: These guys don't know how good they got it.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they're not satisfied if you don't get $15, $20, $30, $40 a day to eat on.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: How did you like pitching in Baker Bowl?
[SPEAKER_02]: That was a wonderful place to pitch.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_02]: Was that right field fence?
[SPEAKER_02]: I'll tell you.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'll never forget the first game I ever pitched there.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was against Eppa Rixey.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I beat Eppa one to nothing.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_02]: And how I ever did it, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes, sir, I beat up on that in Baker's Bowl, one to nothing.
[SPEAKER_04]: I thought everybody hit home runs in Baker Bowl.
[SPEAKER_04]: That right field fence, it was so short.
[SPEAKER_04]: Didn't you feel nervous there with that short fence?
[SPEAKER_04]: You didn't get nervous, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: I was pretty good in that bowl.
[SPEAKER_02]: We went in there one year, we was fighting for the pennant.
[SPEAKER_02]: and went in there one year for a four-game series.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I think it was, I don't know what year it was, but Street said, I'm going to pitch you two games.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I did, and I won both of my games.
[SPEAKER_02]: I always was pretty lucky in Bakers Bowl.
[SPEAKER_04]: What other parks did you like to pitch in?
[SPEAKER_04]: How about the polo grounds?
[SPEAKER_04]: with those short foul lines?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I didn't mind them all around so bad.
[SPEAKER_04]: You make them hit the center field, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: Cubs Park, I didn't like that too well.
[SPEAKER_04]: Why was that?
[SPEAKER_04]: Long fields.
[SPEAKER_02]: What else did I add on my mind there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you want to say something?
[SPEAKER_02]: Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_02]: I like to pitch at Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you like Sportsman's Park?
[SPEAKER_04]: Was that a good one?
[SPEAKER_04]: Your home park?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, I didn't mind Sportsman's Park so bad.
[SPEAKER_00]: You mind having your picture taken?
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm not very presentable for a picture.
[SPEAKER_04]: She's my camera girl.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's just my excuse for coming along.
[SPEAKER_04]: I like to get pictures of these people I'm interviewing.
[SPEAKER_04]: And I'd like to get some pictures of your mementos in there, too, after a bit here.
[SPEAKER_02]: I have most of those are up at the... Cooperstown?
[SPEAKER_02]: Cooperstown.
[SPEAKER_04]: I see some baseballs.
[SPEAKER_04]: Take what you want in there.